Hello everyone, welcome to this session
about expense agent travel and policy
automation.
I am going to start showing you directly
the demo about this new feature. So here
I am in my business central environment
and I have my expense agent already
activated.
If I go to settings now, I can find a
new section here which is called policy
compliance. And this allows me to
activate this evaluate compliance with
AI toggle as well as enable
presubmission evaluation. Let me walk
you through these two options very
quickly.
So evaluate compliance with AI, first of
all, it's a new feature that can use
copilot credits. So um make sure you
check our documentation for the updated
pricing regarding this. And the idea is
um companies have policies that apply to
expenses and some of the policies are
not as easy to check. Um they cannot be
automated in a very simple way. So the
idea is we want to help the approvers to
make decisions about expenses that are
submitted to them. And AI can do this
very nicely by just analyzing some free
text policies that you can add to your
business central environment.
So here for example I can see some
expense policies I have set up before
this session and you can see that I have
different categories to which the
policies apply. So for example I have
airline category or meals or gift and
these of course are all the categories
that you might have in your system. You
can also have custom ones. Um you can
also see that there's multiple um
possible expense policies for the same
category. And the idea is every policy
should be a different line. So you
shouldn't have everything about airlines
just in the same line just because
that's the category. But you can just
split it up so the agent can do a better
job and analyze them just one by one.
In my example, for example, here I have
that um airline tickets cannot be in
first class for my company. And I have
an additional one which is business
class is allowed but only on longhaul
flights. And this is also interesting
because it's something that um it's not
necessarily easy to determine for an
automated system, but it's something
that the AI on the other hand can very
easily determine and evaluate. As I
mentioned, um the idea for policies is
that they are going to help the approver
make a decision. But we also want the
person that submits an expense to be
able to evaluate policies sometimes just
because then maybe they can fix some of
the policy uh discrepancies that they
have before they submit it to the
approver. And that's why you can enable
the presubmission evaluation that the
submitter can run. Um, if you prefer,
you can also just turn it off in case
you're worried, for example, about your
users using too many AI credits or just
abusing of the system. But in general,
um, we think this can just help
submission and just save time for the
submitter and for the approver. So, I'll
confirm my changes. Actually, I didn't
do any change, but I'll just close this,
um, this window and just move directly
to the expense agent web app. Now, now
we're back to the expense agent web web
application or dashboard if you prefer.
And as you can see, I have already some
expense reports that I have uploaded
before with my receipts and everything.
And for example, you can see that some
of them, for example, this first one is
already marked as compliant, but I also
have some that have been marked as
flagged. This is a new status that means
that there are policies that have been
flagged about this expense report.
So if I expand this report, you can see
that I have two lines in this expense
report and one of them is compliant, but
the other one has a flag or something
that needs to be raised to the approver.
So here you can see that when I open
this one up, this expense, I have to the
right the expense policy validation um
evaluation and you can see that here the
AI raised that I have policy that says
that one star hotels are are prohibited.
But in this case, this receipt doesn't
really contain or doesn't really have
information about whether this hotel is
one star or more. Um, so in this case,
the receipt was flagged because the
system was not able to evaluate. And in
this case, unfortunately, it will be the
approver that needs to evaluate whether
this policy is compliant or not.
On the other hand, I have a flight
received here.
So if I make it a little bit larger, you
can see that this is a flight uh from
Orlando through New York to Frankfurt.
So this is um long haul flight, but also
it's an economy. So as you can as you've
seen previously, this is actually very
compliant. Um I could actually even have
booked a business flight for this uh
hole since it's like a longhaul flight.
But in my case, there's no policy um
evaluation like flagged for this one.
And everything looks compliant. And if
we go back here, you can see that I have
an additional um expense report here
which contains some expenses that have
not yet evaluated against my policies.
So the system recognizes that there are
policies pending for some of these and
they're not being yet evaluated. So as a
submitter since in the setup I allowed
submission evaluation I can just click
check policies with AI
and before I send this to my approver
the system will evaluate the available
policies in Business Central against my
expense report. Um and this will take
just a minute and then it will tell me
whether um my expenses are compliant for
my policies or they are not.
And now you can see that just in a few
seconds the flagged here the sorry the
status badge flipped and it says that
now it's flagged and as you can see one
of my receipt was flagged and in a
second to the right you will see that
this reason the reason is that the meal
includes alcoholic beverages in the
itemization. This also gives me
opportunity to mention one more thing
which is that of course for the AI
policy evaluation to have all the
additional information that it needs. We
also need to have itemization of the
receipts whenever possible. So that's
also some new feature that is going to
come soon. We plan to have more um
itemization for receipts so that all the
information that the AI needs to
evaluate for example in this case the
presence of alcohol in meals is going to
be there and it's going to be ready for
the AI to consume. One more thing I want
to mention is that of course policies um
apply to the specific version of the
receipt. So in some case you might have
to change the receipt or change some
description. So in this case I might
have a different merchant name or a
wrong description. So for example here I
could add plus theertert or something
like that and um this is just like a
small sample but I just want to demo
that also the policy applies to the
latest version. So in case I change my
my uh expense you can see that here the
status flag flipped to policies pending.
And now it's clear again that the
policies have not been evaluated to the
latest version of this record. But I
need to run a new evaluation if I want
to um make sure that I'm still
compliant. But as I mentioned initially,
this is actually a feature mostly
thought for the approvers. So that means
that as a submitter, I can still submit
an expense report even if policies are
still pending. It just means that I as a
submitter will just not um have the
opportunity to fix whatever policy
compliance um issue there might be. But
that will be on my approver to decide.
So here I can still click submit even
though the policies have not really been
evaluated against the latest record and
this will also still succeed and will
send my report for approval to my
approver uh setup in business central.
Now in my case also for the ease of demo
but also let's say that I'm in a small
company I am my own approver for
expenses. If I refresh my data for a
second, I will see the report I just
submitted in here. And you can see that
in the meantime, the system evaluated
policies again. And we would expect that
since nothing really changed um in this
policy, we are expecting a new text as
you can see um with the same policy like
issue which is that alcohol cannot be
expenses and yet it's present in this
expense.
Once again, um these policies are more
um like a guidance or maybe a help for
the approver. So I can still override
the policies and decide to approve as a
as an approver even though there is a
policy issue. Um we have upcoming that
it's going to be mandatory for the for
the approver to actually specify a
reason when they override a policy. For
example, if there's a um like why
they're revindring this policy because
this is of course going to be um kept in
business central through the records of
um audit records for the approval for uh
this specific expense report.
Last thing I wanted to mention, I
actually forgot to say it before, is
that of course if there is no policy to
check um then the system will not even
allow like um the submitter to just
check policies because of course that's
nothing to check against. And that's the
same in case my expense report is
already up to date. Then there will be
no reason for the system of course to
run another policy check on a record or
on a policy that has not changed. And
this is all I have for today. Thank you
for your attention.
>> [music]